Trey Hamilton | Software Developer

treyhamilton23@outlook.com
218 368-3779
https://www.linkedin.com/in/trey-hamilton-8739b7126/
https://github.com/treyham91

Profile

Development experience primarily within the .NET framework, SQL Server database development and reporting services, object oriented development using C#, advanced level SharePoint administration along with mid-level development knowledge, and Agile software development methodology industry skills.

I'm a team-oriented developer who focuses on good communication and well-designed code to work well with my team members. Taking business requirements and converting them into a well-operating software product is my goal on every task or project I work on. My technical knowledge, communication skills, and business competency allow me to accomplish all of those things.

Technical Summary

Languages Python, JavaScript, C#, SQL, R

Technologies SQL Server, Visual Studio, .NET framework, SharePoint

(Admin/Development), React.js, jQuery, Node.js, Django, Angular 2, REST

APIs, HTML, CSS, Python machine learning, SQL Server Reporting

Services, WinForms

Databases SQL Server, Oracle, MongoDB, SQLite

OS Windows, OSX

Work Experience

Programmer Analyst - Uponor North America

August 2018 - Present

Promoted to Programmer Analyst after working with Uponor as an intern for over a year. During that time I gained industry knowledge and grew in technical skill, which allowed me to obtain a full-time position.

- Built brand new SharePoint subsite for company managers using a combination of SharePoint webparts, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I handle a majority of the SharePoint development and admin work.
- Enhance and maintain internal business applications for various departments including Supply Chain,
 Quality Control, and our internal MES system.
- Create reports with SQL Server Reporting Services, typically by writing stored procedures in SQL Server and exporting them into report tables.

IT Intern - Uponor North America

June 2017 – August 2018

I obtained an IT internship with Uponor during the summer of 2017, the summer after my junior year of college. Once my pre-determined internship had ended, Uponor offered for me to stay on and help them while I was still in school.

- Obtained industry knowledge and technical skill through various tasks and small SQL reports that I was asked to create.
- Created a C# console application that processes SharePoint workflows into JIRA user stories.
- Gained knowledge in Agile software development, participating on a Manufacturing Application scrum team.

Warehouse/Networking Assistant - Relay Networks August 2016 – June 2017

- Helped maintain inventory of computer, outdoor wireless, and other networking equipment.
- SharePoint site collection administrator, handling almost all of the new development work.
- Organized the warehouse using an Inventory Management System.
- Aided with computer hardware or software troubleshooting.

Help Desk Assistant - Metropolitan State University August 2016 – June 2017

- Fielded phone calls from students and other faculty members on technical issues
- Logged ticket support using Oracle RightNow
- Helped maintain technical upkeep of classrooms

Education

Metropolitan State University
Computer Information Technology
August 2016 - May 2018

Bemidji State University
Computer Information Systems

August 2014 - May 2016

Udemy Training

React 16.6 - The Complete Guide

MERN Stack Front to Back - Full Stack React, Redux & Node.js

Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Machine Learning A-Z: Hands-On Python & R in Data Science

Volunteer

Computer Security and Forensics Student Organization
Metropolitan State University
Vice President

EDUCATIO N

COMPUTER INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY/AUGUST

2018 Metropolitan State University GPA: 3.0 Courses:
Programming Fundamentals, Programming with Objects,
Web Design, Internet Application Development, Database
Management, Organization of Programming Languages,
Computer Security, Software Design Models, Operating
Systems I & II

UDEMY Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp Machine Learning A-Z; Hands-on Python & R in Data Science

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE OR LEADERSHIP

VICE PRESIDENT Computer Security and
Forensics Student Organization Metropolitan State
University Dates from December 2016 – June
2017